Mohammad Hassan

Frontend Developer | Seeking Entry-Level Programming Position

Dhaka 1205 mustakim13579@gmail.com 01890316871

Hello! I am Mohammad Mustakim Hassan and I am a software engineer working on web applications and web infrastructure. I have been developing professionally for 1.5 years but tinkering since 2016. I started in tech with internships, freelance services and part time positions during college.

I have a bit off a diverse job history. I have had positions in help desk, graphic/web design, web app development and sysadmin/devops. I can help everywhere in the stack and I love wearing multiple hats to an extent. Although, I do think my most strongest skills are in Frontend Development.

Work Experience

Freelance WordPress Developer

www.harmious.com - Dhaka April 2020 to September 2020

Built website for small fashion & clothing import business startup with WordPress. I also trained them to use the system POS and provided tech support for the business.

Volunteer Teacher

Hubei University of Technology - Wuhan, Hubei June 2019 to July 2019

Hubei University of Technology sends multiple group of Chinese students annually to small villages in neighboring provinces. In 2019, 4 out of 2000+ international students were selected by the international office to join the Chinese students on volunteering teaching mission in Shanxi, Anhui, China. The program was 2 weeks long. We taught & organized 2 cultural program in the village community center where the students performed 2 drama, debate, group dance and sang.

Video Production Specialist

Mohsin Enterprise - Dhaka November 2018 to November 2018

Mohsin Enterprise is the sole importer & distributor of Deco Prima and other organic fertilizer of Indonesian company PT. Prima Agrotech. I was contacted to compose a 25-30 sec animated video describing the product and the use. The video was used as a primary mode to train farmers and villagers on it's use across various district in Bangladesh. It was made with PowerPoint, Adobe Illustrator and svg icon and primitives.

Education

University in Computer Science

Hubei University of Technology - Wuhan, Hubei

Skills

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Git
- NuxtJS
- Tailwind CSS
- Node.js
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Linux
- JavaScript
- HTML5
- GitHub
- Computer Science
- Java
- MySQL
- AWS
- XML
- REST
- C/C++
- User Interface (UI)

Languages

- Mandarin Intermediate
- Bengali Expert
- English Fluent
- Hindi Intermediate

Links

https://github.com/viceroyshayer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/viceroyshayer/

Certifications and Licenses

IELTS

May 2015 to Present

Scored 7.5 out of 9

- 1. Listening 8
- 2. Reading 8
- 3. Writing 6.5
- 4. Speaking 6.5